A Guide to the Pioneer America Society Records, 1929-1984 (bulk 1968-1976)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Pioneer America Society Records 1929-1984 (bulk 1968-1976)
The Library of Virginia
40235
7 cu. ft. (20 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donor information unavailable.
Biographical Information
The Pioneer America Society was founded in July 1967 and officially incorporated in December 1968 in Virginia. The founder and executive director was Henry H. Douglas (1903-1987). The Society's mission was to record and document the evidence of America's cultural landscape, architecture, and artifacts and encourage educational programs, scholarly research, and preservation. The organization published the newsletters, "Pioneer America" and "Echoes of History." In 1976 due to financial deficits the Society was disbanned and publication of "Echoes of History" was discontinued. At a later point the organization was re-established and is currently active (2006).
Scope and Content
Records, 1929-1984 (bulk 1968-1976) of the Pioneer America Society, based in Falls Church, Virginia. The files were collected by Henry H. Douglas, Executive Director of the Pioneer Society of America and were maintained in their original order. The records are arranged into two series: 1. State/Country Files and 2. Subject Files.
The records document the efforts of the organization to detail and record information on historical buildings, landscapes, people, and towns in America. The files include brochures, clippings, correspondence, data sheets, maps, photographs, and postcards. Also included are various newsletters from local and national organizations. The collection does not contain any of the organizations internal files such as financial records, membership lists, or minutes, although some correspondence is included. Rather the collection consists of files the organization gathered for information purposes on subjects they considered important for their mission of documenting America's historic treasures.
Series I: State/Country Files, 1929-1984 (bulk 1968-1978). This series consists of booklets, clippings, correspondence, newsletters, photographs, and postcards collected on various conservation topics. The files are arranged by state name and includes some foreign country files such as China, Japan, Russia, and Siberia. Topics include the documentation of the towns and villages in America; the history of canals, farms, forts, gold mines, mills, and railroads; how growth of cities threaten historical sites; and efforts and grants by individuals, societies, and the government to save historic sites. Also includes brochures from museums, historical sites, and local tourist bureaus across the country. Includes newsletters from the American Canal Society, Kansas Historical Society Mirror, The Long Island in History Series, Montana Post, Pennsylvania Heritage, and Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission. The files on Maryland and Virginia are the most complete, with files for cities and counties in the state.
Of note are the data sheets, prepared by the Pioneer America Society. These data sheets include information on various buildings and people noted for their historical significance. The sheets include the location and coordinates, photographs, and notes. The photographs are of various historic buildings such as churches, farms, homes, post offices, and schools, and of local people. Some of the data sheets also include notes and descriptions of the buildings, especially if a photograph is not attached. These data sheets are informative, but unfortunately very dispersed within the collection. Most can be found within the Pennsylvania and Virginia files.
Also included are letters to Henry H. Douglas from other organizations asking for copies of books or newsletters published by the society, from members, and sharing information to be included in the society's newsletter. Also included are files on William E. Barrett (b. 1927), a photographer from Clifton, Virginia. He donated photographs to be used in the publications, Echoes of History and Pioneer America. Included are copies of photographs and images from a calendar of historic structures in Virginia.
Series II: Subject Files, 1937-1983 (bulk 1970-1975). This series also consists of booklets, clippings, magazine articles, minutes, newsletters, and postcards collected on various conservation topics, arranged by subject, rather than by location. Subject files include architecture, automobiles, bicentennial, blast furnaces, circuses, civil war, covered bridges, farming, Indians, Thomas Jefferson, lime kilns, living history, money raising, National Endowment for the Humanities, people, photography, pollution, preservation, railroads, rivers, roads, tobacco, trolleys, George Washington, wilderness, and Zeppelins, among others.
Includes newsletters from the American Folklore Society, Bicentennial Newsletter, Council on Abandoned MIlitary Posts, Early Man, The Headway Recorder (National Capital Historical Museum of Transportation) Living Historical Fams Bulletin, Lynchburg Historical Society, Old Mills News, Pennsylvania Canal Society, Shenandoah Vallye Folklore Society, Society for Industrial Archeology, Society of Architectural Historians, and the Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission.
Arrangement
Arranged into two series: Series I: State/Country Files and Series II: Subject Files.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Contents List
- Series I: State/Country Files 1929-1984 (bulk 1968-1978)
  - Alabama, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alaska, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arizona, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - California, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Canada, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - China, 1944-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - China, Bibliography, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - China, Chiang Kai-Shek, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - China, Photography, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - China, Provinces, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - China, Supply routes, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Colorado, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Delaware, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - DC/Georgetown/Key Bridge, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - DC/Georgetown/Key Bridge, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - DC/Georgetown/Key Bridge, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Florida, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Georgia, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hawaii, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Illinois, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Indiana, 1939-1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Indiana, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Iowa, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Japan, 1927-1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kansas, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kentucky, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Louisiana, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Maine, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Maryland, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Maryland, Architecture, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Maryland, Bridges, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Maryland, Canals, 1959-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Maryland, Canal, Chesapeake and Ohio, 1968-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Maryland, Cemeteries, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Maryland, Farms, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Maryland, Ferries, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Maryland, Forts, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Maryland, Gold Mines, 1971-1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Maryland, Growth, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Maryland, Inns/Taverns, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Maryland, Lighthouses, Nd (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Maryland, Parks, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Maryland, Places, 1966-1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Maryland, Preservation, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Maryland, Railroads, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Maryland, Roads, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Maryland, Annapolis, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Maryland, Baltimore, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Maryland, Barnesville, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Maryland, Buckeystown, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Maryland, Charles County, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Maryland, Chesapeake Bay, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Maryland, Chesapeake Beach, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Maryland, Claiborne, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Maryland, Eastern Shore, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Maryland, Frederick, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Maryland, Frederick, Catoctin Furnace, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Maryland, Garrett Park, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Maryland, Harford County, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Maryland, Howard County, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Maryland, Kent Island, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Maryland, Montogmery County, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Maryland, Montgomery County, Forest Glen, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Maryland, Montgomery County, Grist mills, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Maryland, Montgomery County, Parks, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Maryland, Oxford, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Maryland, Port Tobacco, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Maryland, Prince George County, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Maryland, Rehoboth, Nd (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Maryland, Rockville, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Maryland, St. Mary's, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Maryland, St. Michael's, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Maryland, Sandy Spring, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Maryland, Southern, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Maryland, Thurmont, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Maryland, Tilghman Island, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Massachusetts, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Michigan, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Michigan, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minnesota, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Mississippi, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Missouri, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Montana, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Montana, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Montana, Newsletter Montana Post, 1966-1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Nebraska, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Nevada, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - New England, Nd (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - New Hampshire, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New Mexico, Nd (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New York, 1967-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ohio, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Oklahoma, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Oregon, 1968-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Panama, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pennsylvania, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania, Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania, Data sheets, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania, Newsletter Pennsylvania Heritage, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania, Railroads, Nd (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rhode Island, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Siberia, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - South Carolina, 1969-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - South Dakota, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Southwest, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee, 1970-1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Texas, 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - USSR, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - US 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - US, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - US, Wilderness, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Utah, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Vermont, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Virginia, 1958-1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Virginia, Archaeology, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Virginia, Architecture, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Virginia, Bridges, 1975-1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Virginia, Canals, 1966-1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Virginia, Canals, Alexandria, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Virginia, Churches, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Virginia, Civil War, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Virginia, Dams, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Virginia, Fences, Nd (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Virginia, Ferries, 1971-1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Virginia, Grist mill, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Virginia, Highways, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Virginia, Historic houses/gardens, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Virginia, Hunt country, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Virginia, Indians, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Virginia, Landmarks, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Virginia, Land use, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Virginia, Mountains, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Virginia, Museums, Nd (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Virginia, People, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Virginia, Place names, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Virginia, Preservation, 1958-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Virginia, Railroads, 1968-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Virginia, Rivers, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Virginia, Roads, 1931-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, Storms, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Virginia, Trees, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Virginia, Wetlands, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Virginia, Accomack County, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Virginia, Albemarle County, 1968-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Virginia, Alleghany County, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Virginia, Amelia County, Nd (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Virginia, Amherst County, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Virginia, Appalachians, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Virginia, Appomattox County, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Virginia, Augusta County, 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Virginia, Bath County, 1943-1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Virginia, Botetourt County, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Virginia, Buckingham County, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Virginia, Campbell County, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Virginia, Caroline County, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Virginia, Carroll County, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Virginia, Charles City County, Nd (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Virginia, Chesapeake, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Virginia, Clarke County, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Virginia, Culpepper County, 1968-1984 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Virginia, Cumberland County, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Virginia, Dinwiddie County, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Virginia, Eastern Shore, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Virginia, Fauquier County, Barns-Floods, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Virginia, Fauquier County, Gold Mines-Oral history, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Virginia, Fauquier County- Orderaries-Towns and Villages, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Virginia, Fauquier County, A-M, 1967-1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, Fauquier County, P-W, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Virginia, Fluvanna County, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Virginia, Franklin County, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Virginia, Frederick County, 1967-1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Virginia, Fredericksburg, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Virginia, Gloucester County, Nd (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Virginia, Goochland County, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Virginia, Greene County, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Virginia, Halifax County, Nd (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Virginia, Hanover County, Nd (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Virginia, Henrico County, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Virginia, Highland County, 1968-1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Virginia, Highland County, Bullpasture Gorge, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Virginia, Higland County, Bullpasture Mountain, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, Highland County, Bullpasture Valley, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Virginia, Highland County, Burnsville Valley, 1967-1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Virginia, Highland County, Cowpasture Valley, 1929-1968 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Virginia, Highland/Monterey Town and Valley, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Virginia, Isle of Wight County, Nd (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Virginia, King George County, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Virginia, King and Queen County, 1964-1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Virginia, Lancaster County, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Virginia, Lee County, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Virginia, Madison County, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Virginia, Montgomery County, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Virginia, Nelson County, 1969-1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Virginia, Nelson County, Floods, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Virginia, Norfolk County, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Virginia, Northern Neck, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Virginia, Northern Virginia, 1966-1974 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Virginia, Orange County, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Virginia, Page County, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Virginia, Patrick County, Nd (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Virginia, Piedmont, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Virginia, Pittsylvania County, Nd (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Virginia, Prince George County, Nd (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Virginia, Rappahannock County, 1969-1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Virginia, Richmond, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, Roanoke County, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Virginia, Rockbridge County, 1967-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Virginia, Rockingham County, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Virginia, Shenandoah County, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Virginia, Shenandoah County, Furnaces, Nd (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Virginia, Shenandoah County, Grist mills, Nd (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Virginia, Shenandoah Valley, 1969-1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Virginia, Smyth County, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Virginia, Southwest Virginia, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Virginia, Spotsylvania County, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Virginia, Stafford County, 1969-1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Virginia, Surry County, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Virginia, Tangier Island, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Virginia, Warren County, 1958-1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Virginia, Warwick County, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Virginia, Washington County, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Virginia, Westmoreland County, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - West Virginia, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - West Virginia, Oil wells, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - West Virginia, Berkeley County, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - West Virginia, Hardy County, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - West Virginia, Jefferson County, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - West Virginia, Morgan County, Nd (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - West Virginia, Pendleton, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - West Virginia, Pocahontas County, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - West Virginia, Tuckahoe County, Nd (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Washington, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - West, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Western Reserve, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Wisconsin, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Wyoming, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - William E. Barrett,1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - William E. Barrett, Bridges, Cemeteries, Mills of Virginia and West Virginia, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - William E. Barrett, Railroad stations, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - William E. Barrett, Baltimore, Maryland, Nd (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - William E. Barrett, Cumberland, Maryland, Nd (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - William E. Barrett, Alexandria, Virginia, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - William E. Barrett, Arlington, Virginia, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - William E. Barrett, Culpepper, Virginia, Nd (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - William E. Barrett, Fairfax County, Virginia, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - William E. Barrett, Fauquier County, Virginia, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - William E. Barrett, Loudoun County, Virginia, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - William E. Barrett, Prince William County, Virginia, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - William E. Barrett, Stafford County, Virginia, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - William E. Barrett, Morgantown, West Virginia, Nd (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Series II: Subject files, 1937-1983 (bulk 1970-1975)
  - Adaptive uses, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - America the Beautiful, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Bibliographical Center, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Folklore Society, 1972-1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Revolution, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - American Work Horse Museum Inc., 1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Amish, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Antiques, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Antique shows, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Antiquities, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Appalachia, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Appalachian Trail, 1954-1973 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Appraisals, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Archaeology, 1966-1975 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Archaeology Society of Virginia, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Architecture, 1969-1980 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Archives, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Archives Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Arlington Historical Society, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Association for Preservation Technology, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Automobiles, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Barbed wire, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Barns, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Beaver, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Bells, Nd (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Bicentennial, Kiwanis, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Bicentennial, National, 1971-1976 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Bicentennial, Shenandoah County, Nd (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Bicentennial, Virginia, 1972-1977 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Bike trails, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Biographies, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Blacksmiths, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Blast furnaces, Nd (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Boats, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Books, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Book dealers, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Brady, Matthew, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Brick, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Bridges, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Buckland, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cabins, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Camp meetings, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Cemeteries, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cemetery forms, Blank, Nd (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Certificates, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Chestnuts, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Chimneys, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Churches, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Circuses, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cities, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Civil War, 1959-1975 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Civil War, Roundtables, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Civil War, Roundtables, Alexandria, 1973-1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Colored people, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Columbia Historical Society, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Conservation, 1965-1977 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Council on Abandoned Military Posts, 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Courthouses, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Covenants and easements, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Covered bridges, 1968-1972 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - County histories, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Crafts, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Declaration of Independence, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Dams, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Development, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - District of Columbia, 1974-1979 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Douglas, Henry H., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Doukhobors, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Dwellings, Nd (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - DuVal, Clive, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Earth, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Eastern Historical Geography Association, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Ecology, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Enegry, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Energy crisis, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Entertainment, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Farming, 1970-1977 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Fences, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ferries, Nd (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Field trip, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Films, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Financial projection, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Fire engines, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Fisher, Joe, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Flax, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Floods, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Folklore, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Forts, Virginia, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Foxfire, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Genealogy, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Ghosts, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ghost towns, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Glass, Nd (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Glenbow Foundation, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Godey's Lady Book, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Grants, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Grist mills, 1972-1983 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Growth, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 26)